Hey, welcome back.
We're playing Chants of Sonora.
I don't know why that was so funny to say, but I'm going through the hole.
Let's do it.
Whoa.
Devotee... must need...
Hmm.
Must not see me with you?
You and me go to the city.
Oh shit.
You know a secret entrance?
Must need...
I think must need is wrong here.
What's happening here?
Must not find you?
Devotees must not find you or me.
Ahh!
That's what that means.
100%.
This has to be find.
Or search.
Wait a minute.
Hold on.
Does that make sense?
What did I put this one as?
Do we have that up here?
I think this one is wrong.
We definitely have must slash need wrong here.
Devotee...
cannot find us.
I think this means us, you and me.
This is walking, right?
There's no...
There's no doubt about that.
This one is hiding.
You, me, go to the city.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That makes sense.
This one though.
Am I about to hide from this guy?
Yeah, because I'm breaking into a place I'm not supposed to be, right?
I tried to enter the normal way and the guy had a quick look at me and went like, nope, and closed the shutter on me.
So I think this means...
Then again, devotee refers to...
the people in here, right?
It's not me.
I'm not a devotee.
I'm just a human.
A citizen, right?
I'm gonna say...
But where did this one pop up as well?
Ah, it was because you found me, right?
I
think it belongs there.
But how does this make sense here then?
If that is find, then this one has to be something else.
Otherwise it would pop up here if find makes sense.
devotee must slash need...
Uh, hmm...
I don't know.
We'll have to see.
Oh yeah, we're totally hiding.
Oh shit, how do I move?
I follow, I follow you.
Wait, what?
Nice distraction, kid.
Okay.
I can do that.
Some areas must be crossed without being noticed.
Hover over a hiding place until a silhouette appears, then click to go there.
Oh, cool.
Okay.
Throw it.
I can aim?
What if I aim at him?
Oh, okay.
I gotta aim at this.
Check it out.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Oh, what's this?
I got sand.
I don't know why, but I got it.
Can I throw it at something?
All right.
I think we're good here.
Okay.
So what do you got?
Yumi mustn't... yeah, go to the temple, yes.
The devotee closed the door.
Wait, the devotee?
I thought you meant the warriors closed the door.
Probably a different door.
Yumi find...
something.
Not quite sure what that is.
What are we finding?
What do you got there?
A key.
It's key for sure.
That's what you need to open the door, right?
Yumi, we find key.
Got it.
I can help you find the key.
Unless you already found it.
I can search down...
Oh, I see something glinting.
Aha!
Hey, kid, don't bother.
I found it.
Yay!
Collected items are added to the inventory.
Click on the icon of an item to open it.
From the inventory, you can observe your items closely and rotate them.
Oh, that's neat.
Very nice.
You find key.
Yumi...
eat.
Okay, that's probably not what that means.
Wait, wait, wait.
Huh?
Some elements of the environment can be combined with items from your inventory.
To combine them, first click on the element, choose your item, then click on the combine button.
Okay.
I see.
Ah, right.
There we go.
Open the door.
Okay.
Let's go.
Lovely little environments here.
Hello.
Oh, look, we got devotees here.
Yeah, goodbye, kid.
I'll talk to you later.
All right.
You know what?
I think this means ascend or climb.
I think that's what the kid told me before.
The kid needed to climb.
And then the kid also told me we should climb or go up.
I think this means up.
But this right here is super confusing.
Escape.
This means stop or halt.
Oh, man, I don't know what to put in here.
Help.
Must need.
This one was found something with hiding.
Eat.
Yeah, this one is wrong.
I think this one means up or ascend, climb.
For sure.
Let's just throw that one in there.
Boom.
Just like that.
Nice.
Okay.
We could go talk to these guys who are just sort of wandering.
Are you not going to wander why I'm in here?
Oh, wait, what?
I can become part of the thing.
Why would I want to do that?
Blend in.
Interesting.
Where are we going?
Maybe they're going to go somewhere special now that I'm following them.
I'm terrible at this.
I'm not blending in at all.
I'm missing the headpiece.
I'm not a true devotee.
Okay.
Well, we have other places to go.
Let's go this way.
Very nice city, this.
Beautiful.
Okay, there's something over here.
A statue.
Oh, is this the head devotee?
God calls us.
God calls to us.
That makes sense.
All right.
I can also go up over here.
Or I can go up here.
Oh, man, so many paths to take.
Let's try this one.
Oh, hello there.
Oh, look, the plants are dying.
Oh, plants, crops are dead.
I am so sure that I'm correct with that now.
Me must need plants, crops.
We must save the crops.
I need water.
Could that mean water?
How about you have water here?
What do you mean?
Me must need fine water.
You're kidding me, right?
You have water right over there.
You're talking about water.
You must talk about water.
Or nutrients or something.
Okay, okay, okay.
Oh, man.
Yeah, the plants are dying.
Cat-o!
Little cat, I can't pet it.
No, what a tragedy.
I need to pet that cat.
That's a rule.
What do we got over here?
Sir, I would bring you water, but...
Yeah.
Me, I must...
save...
the dead plants.
It's got to mean save, right?
Let's say that's save.
Rescue.
Save slash rescue restore.
Plants, crops are dead.
Me needs to find...
I'm going to say this means water.
Water...
needs...
But if that means water, then this one starts with water.
And does that make sense?
I'm not sure.
Maybe clean water.
Also, what's the last one?
Water needs a bucket?
Maybe it doesn't have a bucket.
Let me say that's water.
It's a very tentative one.
Two stars on that.
And this guy up here...
Let's say it's a bucket.
Or container.
Water needs a container.
Me must find water.
Plants are dead.
I must save the dead plants.
That makes sense to me.
I will help you, sir.
Look, some of the plants are alive, though.
In fact, there's been plenty of plants that are thriving here.
But definitely a lot of them are dead.
Ooh, a door!
Probably needs a key, right?
It's like, huh?
Can't do anything about that.
I need that key.
Okay, buddy.
Let's go up here.
Ooh!
Son!
Let me see if I can read this before clicking on it.
So God...
Uh...
Revitalizes...
Or rescues...
Devotees...
And some other type of human.
Oh, you and me, of course!
So us...
God...
Holds us.
Carries us.
Embraces us.
Protects us.
Protects us!
It's got to mean protect!
That makes the most sense.
Right?
Oh, also, it's, uh...
That dude, so it is that guy.
Let's say, protect.
Slash, save.
I think it's protect.
God saves us.
God protects us.
The sun protects us.
Makes sense to me.
I love this music.
Who's playing it?
It sounds like someone is playing it.
Are you playing it?
You are!
Look at him vibing!
Aw, that's nice.
Hey, bro!
Me, protect...
My friend?
Or singer?
Huh, what could that mean?
Now I'm thinking, could it be listen?
I listen.
What could that mean?
Maybe music.
Very unsure about that.
Maybe he's saying, I protect the music, as in, I'm keeping the musical arts alive.
Probably not, but who knows?
Can't talk to the dude down here.
Let me go down these stairs.
Let's go up here.
By the way, it just occurred to me.
Maybe he said, I love music.
And this one down there with the hands, couldn't mean, God loves us.
You know what?
Let me put that in before I forget.
The one with the hand... love...
was...
Let's do protect slash love.
Hey there, buddy!
What are you up to?
Oh, well, I hear the cat.
You help me.
Yeah, definitely means help.
I can help you.
But I don't have anything.
Pockets are empty, I'm sorry.
I'm gonna have a look around.
Nice cat you got.
What's this?
Ooh!
The components of some devices or mechanisms can be manipulated.
Hover over a component, then hold down the left mouse button to grab it.
Drag the component to the desired position, then release.
Interesting.
Oh, notice the background here.
This is definitely the city, slash temple, where the sun was up top, or a god.
So, this guy, god is definitely on top.
Humans are below.
I would say devotees are one step above, and warriors are above that.
Yeah.
Makes sense.
Let me also have a look at this up here.
God...
kills everyone.
God must need... God requires death?
Maybe I got... I probably got must need wrong here.
Hmm...
What could that mean?
God something dead.
Ah, man, I don't know.
Is this like a place they store corpses?
A morgue?
Some kind of temple?
Temple of the dead?
Is this where you put your dead to rest?
Hey, what is this place?
I'm not permitted to enter?
What if I do it anyway?
You're not gonna let me.
Man, we love the ambiance.
No?
Okay.
Please, there's stuff in there.
I gotta get in there.
Oooh...
It's a church.
Church of the dead?
What's going on?
You need to find God?
I need to find water.
I mean, water could be wrong here, of course.
Okay.
What are you saying?
We need to find water.
You have plenty of water.
Have you seen your aqueducts, though?
I probably got water wrong.
Yeah.
Let me have a look up here.
Oh...
I see.
It's not water.
It's some kind of...
Jesus.
I guess it's the son of God.
Right?
It's the...
What do you call it?
It's the son, or God, in the shape of a human.
Let's call it...
Maybe they're president.
Or leader.
They're king.
That guy.
Maybe Jesus.
I mean, obviously it's not Jesus, but...
I'm just gonna put that there so I know.
Jesus slash leader slash king, you know?
Big figure.
Very important.
Maybe he was lost.
Maybe he disappeared.
Or maybe this is just the embodiment of the son itself, so...
What they're really saying is this is not actually a human.
But they're saying they need sun in that case?
No, that doesn't make sense.
They would need the opposite of sun, right?
Oh, wait!
Rain, perhaps.
So obviously this guy is Jesus.
This here is a plant.
And that is death.
Which is the guy lying down.
Or is it there?
Boom!
Please, I can't wait to see what this is.
Plant!
Fantastic!
Yes?
Preacher!
So wait a minute, the guy trying to rescue the plants?
He doesn't need water.
He needs a preacher?
The hell kind of shit is that?
That's not how you save a plant.
Loving these drawings, by the way.
Very cool.
Very nice.
So the preacher is missing, I guess.
He's not here.
Well, now he is.
I am the new preacher.
Listen up, people.
You don't have to rely on me, okay?
I am not the answer.
You know what your plants really need?
Water, with electrolytes.
It's what they crave.
It will solve the drought, save the greenery, and it does a better job than I ever could.
Thank you.
Now carry on.
Back to work.
So now that we know that, you're saying, I need to find God.
I need to find a preacher.
Because it's their way of communicating with God, maybe.
Maybe they're lost.
They don't know what to do in this situation.
And their preacher is missing.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Oh.
What's happening?
Ahem.
Don't mind me.
Whoo-hoo!
What's this?
Oh, we got all kinds of new symbols here.
Well, two new symbols.
This means some kind of house, I think.
Same as this.
Ah, then again, our container.
Container filled with sun.
Or God.
This one is container filled with that symbol, which is plant.
Container filled with plant.
Oh, pot!
It's totally a pot for a plant, right?
This one could be...
Well, let me have a look here.
What's that?
Protect love.
Oh, what am I trying to say here, though?
Uh, I'm not sure.
I need to take a look over here.
That guy cannot see me.
There we go.
What's this?
New symbols again.
Something with hiding.
Let's see.
Okay.
This is key.
Notice how some of these symbols sort of are combined of different things.
Musical key, this could mean.
Or sound.
Almost looks like a sound wave being emanated, right?
So I can turn these.
What am I trying to say in here?
You.
God.
Are these all the same?
Something...
Hmm.
I don't want to just trial and error this.
I want to try and understand what's going on.
Um...
Do we have any hints as to how that should be done?
Here they come again.
I'm going to just fall in line here.
Get to the other side, see what's going on over there.
These are the worst guards ever, by the way.
How have they not noticed what's going on here?
Ah, here we go.
There we are.
Let's see here.
I don't understand.
I think we may need something for this.
That I don't have.
I think it's time to get out.
I'll be back later.
Sorry, sorry.
I'm so disruptive.
There you are.
I don't have anything for you, I'm sorry.
I'll come back when I do.
I gotta find a coin.
So I can toss it to you.
Let's go this way.
Ooh.
A pillar.
So that is pointing towards...
House of...
Oh wait, was that the new one I just got?
Oh, it's down here.
This is House of Dead.
Then again, I mean, it's obviously just one word, but...
approximately something like that, I think.
Based on my theory here.
Oh, but then again.
What am I saying?
Bucket of Dead.
Container with Dead, but that doesn't make sense.
Actually, I'm not sure what to put there.
This could be some kind of church.
That's where I came from, right?
Actually, oh, yeah, look at this.
House of...
What did I say these were?
City.
That doesn't make sense.
House of City.
I mean, they're just one word.
So maybe I shouldn't put too much thought into the actual shape of this.
Yeah, let's not overthink this right now.
So that one leads to...
This one leads to the church that I was just in.
This one is going to lead to the...
Oh, you know what?
This probably means garden.
Let's see if it leads me back to all the plants.
Yes!
Okay, this has to be a garden.
Right?
That's a garden.
Let's put that in.
So I guess I can pay attention to the shape of this.
Oh, that makes so much sense.
Think about it.
House of Plants is called a garden, or what do you call it?
A greenhouse, right?
AKA greenhouse.
House of God.
Church!
Oh my goodness!
That makes so much sense.
Holy shit.
Church.
And this guy?
House of the Dead?
What do you call that?
Well, it's the morgue.
Right?
Morgue!
House of Dead.
Let me see if I'm right.
So this is garden.
Church, if this is indeed a morgue, I'm going to be so happy.
Nice morgue music.
Got a hole in the wall.
These people really need to fix up their holes here.
Ooh!
This looks very similar to the engravings from the beginning of the game when we emerged.
Remember, there were these shapes on the ground around the stone from which we came.
What is this?
Yeah, lighting up the same way too.
What the?
A TIE fighter!
What the hell?
Wait, what is this?
Is this a video game?
Wait, what's going on?
What is this symbol up here?
Level one?
What's going on here?
I'm trying to establish a connection between...
Richard and myself?
Huh?
Very intrigued by this!
I'll be back for that for sure.
Right now, I'm very confused.
It is what it is, though.
We move on.
Oh, that's a nice color here.
Yeah, graveyard!
Graveyard is what it means.
Of course.
Graves?
Yeah, look, this is a map?
Oh, for sure.
So, yeah, garden...
graveyard...
and church.
And this over here is...
Wait, where is this?
Do we have another house?
I guess I gotta take a look at what that place is first.
Yeah, look.
Hehe, morgue.
Uh, let me change that.
Definitely graveyard is the better way to do it.
So, these all seem like outdoor things, no?
Oh, wait, no, church is inside, so it could be something else.
Graveyard, garden...
church, and this one is definitely...
I think it's that one.
It's the house I couldn't get into.
Yep.
I'm not sure what it is, but, uh...
Abbey.
Oh, that makes sense, I guess.
It's like a little outdoorsy area where you can walk around on the sides here.
Right.
Okay.
Something's going on over here.
Nevermind.
Graves up here.
Who died?
Let me see if I can read this before doing anything else.
So, we have God on the right.
Must need in the center.
And then we have...
I need God.
Church...
helps...
me.
You find God, church help you.
Oh, it's you, not me.
You find God, church will help you.
Okay.
By the way, let's take a look at the earlier pages.
Maybe we can figure something out here.
This one I'm not sure about.
Do we have anything like that?
Something with Haydn.
You know, this could also be...
This is the symbol or glyph we got when talking to the child when we...
tried to pass through undetected.
That could mean this.
You know, we need to escape this place.
Come with me, we gotta do it silently.
This one, however, I'm not sure about.
Something with Stop.
And I don't really have anything like that.
So, these two are also related.
These three are related.
This is a key.
This could be...
I think it's something with...
It's like a gadget.
This is like a gadget.
Something that will help you.
And this is containing a plant.
This could be a garden hose.
And this one could be a musical instrument.
This is music.
Musical instrument.
Perhaps.
It's not quite...
confirmed, I guess.
Okay.
And we also have this over here.
Oh, wait a minute.
Call... Go?
Could be this one.
Walk.
Go.
Actually.
This one is...
hiding.
I'm not sure if it's referring to this act or this act.
Because this act is searching.
This is hiding.
Something with hiding.
Not correct.
Okay.
Now I have one other thing I can try, which is search.
Or find.
This guy.
Notice also how all of them have this line on the bottom.
Ah, but I already guessed this one to be find.
So what is... Wait, what is this one?
Oh, I have two of them.
Oh, no.
Shit.
Obviously something is wrong there.
Let's think about it later.
What's this?
Oh!
I just rotated that guy.
Huh!
What does this one say?
El Gato!
Um...
This one says...
God...
finds us.
Or God... Yeah, God finds us.
God sees us.
He's looking!
See!
Oh, it means see to watch.
That makes so much sense.
Okay, okay, okay.
So we have this guy.
It's got to be see.
It even looks like an eye a little bit.
God sees us.
Yeah.
So if that's correct...
See and search could be the same thing, right?
Ah, then again, never mind this one.
Definitely see.
This is help.
Where's my help?
Help?
That makes sense too.
Look at these two circles interlocking together.
It's like two hands grabbing each other, right?
Ah, this one...
This one is talk or speak.
Hmm.
This could be love.
They love each other.
Right?
Call for someone?
I'm not entirely sure about that yet.
Let's wait a bit.
Okay.
So we have these different statues here, and they can be rotated.
I see one over there too.
And there.
This is the preacher.
This guy is me, I think.
That looks like me.
Do they all need to sort of look towards the center?
Can I rotate it the other way, please?
No?
I gotta go all the way around.
I mean, the obvious thing is to put them like this, right?
If that doesn't work, I'm not gonna trial and error this.
Hey, cat.
Then again, this eye is looking this way.
So maybe all of them need to be facing that way.
Ah, but wait a minute, there's also a pillar over there.
Hold the phone.
What's this?
A sword.
A key.
And then we have a musical instrument.
And the last one...
is a vase.
Or a bottle.
And this one says...
God sees us.
God sees this over here.
So maybe these guys need to be looking towards that.
Let's point them all towards that over there.
It's gonna be a little annoying turning these now again, but...
you know, it is what it is.
So, the question is, what are they seeing?
What best represents us?
Is it the sword?
Is it the music?
Is it the...
Ah, shit, I shouldn't have turned this guy.
Dammit.
This guy was already correct.
Come on.
There.
And then this guy...
that way.
So now I'm thinking, they're all looking at this now.
What best represents us?
Because this says, God sees us.
Or you and me.
Could it be the music?
Or the sword?
I'm not sure.
Okay, I'm not sure.
Nope.
No clue.
God sees us.
Let's see what this one says again.
You find God...
the church will help you.
The key to this puzzle is in the church.
Got it.
Okay, good to know.
Good to know.
Let's move on.
And what's going on with this right over here?
This is so mysterious.
I'm gonna check that out later.
A little video game tucked away...
behind that wall there.
Okay, let's go back to the garden.
By the way, was it actually confirmed that it was called garden?
Yes, it was.
Garden, cemetery...
or yeah, graveyard cemetery, same thing.
Abbey.
Right, so let's see what you have to say now.
Preacher...
must-need garden.
Man, I think must-need is wrong, but what could it be?
Preacher...
saves garden.
made this garden.
Me, must-need.
No, definitely, I'm on the right track with must-need.
Preacher, what does the preacher do to the garden?
He... I don't know.
Plants are dying, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Me, must-need, protect, slash, love.
Ah, must-need.
Want.
I want to protect...
plants that are dead.
I think protect could be wrong here, actually.
I need to love that plant.
Yeah, that doesn't make sense at all, actually.
I think we definitely have these two words super wrong.
The fact that we can't even connect that sentence means we got it super wrong.
Well, that's okay.
We're gonna find more clues.
Let's head, uh...
Did I go this way?
I came from here earlier, I remember that.
Oh, yeah.
Let's go back then.
Right, there's this spot.
We didn't go up here yet.
Yeah, just go up here.
Oh, that takes us here.
I see.
Okay.
Let's go back to the church.
And I'm sorry, buddy, I still don't have any money.
No...
I got no money, sorry.
Oh, actually, go back out.
Look at this thing again.
God...
brings death.
Brings.
Causes death.
That could be it.
How would that play with the conversation we had just before?
Preacher.
Causes...
No, that doesn't make sense.
I'm not sure how this mechanism inside the church even works.
That's the problem now.
I may need to take another look at this.
Get behind these.
Very sneakily.
Incredibly poor at his job this guy is, protecting this area.
So we also have these symbols up top here, whatever that means.
I can't help but feel I'm needing some kind of item to slot into here.
Right, and I don't have it.
Yeah, there's nothing I can do in here.
I gotta figure out...
or find an item that I can slot into the socket there above it.
Let's go back to the beginning, see if we can find anything.
In that sort of area.
In fact, I want to go back to the murals on the wall.
From the very beginning.
Hey there, buddy.
Sorry, yeah, sorry.
Don't have any money.
So that would mean, I guess...
This way towards the abbey.
Ah, but hold on, we snuck past a guy down here.
How are we gonna get out again?
Ah, that's what the other dirt pile was for, I see now.
I get it.
Yeah, look at this.
Very sneaky now.
Oh!
Oh, shit!
Rad!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Oh, fuck!
No!
I got thrown out of the abbey!
Well, that's fair, I guess.
Damn, alright then.
Hey, listen, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to, I just happened to be in there, I got lost.
I was looking for the toilet.
What do you want?
No?
Alright, fine.
You know what, I'm actually happy about this.
This is a fast way out, I guess.
Okay, here we go.
Let me talk to you again.
Now, I have all this new knowledge.
You...
Yeah.
Gotta go door.
Sure.
Now, this over here is very confusing.
Let's have another look at that.
So, there's LL and Sun.
So, what is the point here?
Do I always go for the Sun?
Oh, it changed.
What?
Changed that one?
I don't understand nothing of this.
It's actually insanity.
I feel so stupid, it's wild.
I've got no idea what that means.
Right, you're saying you cannot enter.
God calls for me?
The temple of God?
Me, find, go?
Yeah, find is probably wrong here.
I'm definitely kinda lost right now, I'm not gonna lie.
Let's go back down here.
I wanna get this story right.
Let's see what we know now.
Warriors closing the door.
Why did they close the door though?
And this one?
Devotees...
search for God.
The devotees found God.
Yeah.
And then there's this little thing over here.
Temple City.
There's also a simple behind there, or that is now broken off, we can't see it anymore.
I wonder what that could be.
So we're not getting the full story here.
Gotcha.
Then all the way over here.
Unreadable?
Devotees.
Men.
Became devotees.
Right.
They ascended towards devoteeship.
God calls on humans.
Beckons?
Could be beckon.
God calls slash needs.
I think need is wrong here.
God shines upon humans.
I think call is probably correct.
That would make sense with the book we have.
Call.
Right.
Yep.
Help.
Talk.
Oh, so God communicates with humans.
Love slash like, yeah.
See slash look.
Oh man, I fucking nailed it.
Yes, sir.
Very nice.
God speaking to men.
So being shone on by the light is akin to being spoken to in this world by God.
Men unreadable, plants dying.
Also, are these supposed to be humans?
Next to the plants dying.
Okay.
Very nice.
Well, that's a big thing we just figured out.
Let me open the book again.
We also had a couple other pages here.
This guy.
I think this means whatever this is.
Oh, never mind.
So how does that make sense with the conversation we had with the kids?
He said something like devotees cannot see us.
Oh, that makes sense, actually.
Don't let them see us.
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That makes sense.
Now, this guy and this guy are obviously not working together.
I think this is correct.
This means escape, right?
Your escape.
But I don't have anything like that.
Must need...
Hmm.
Okay.
I'm gonna take a break here.
I'll see you in the next episode.
Thanks for watching.
Bye-bye.